I have a love in my life. It makes me stronger than anything you can imagine.
Punch-Drunk Love is a romance, drama, comedy film
directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
A socially awkward and volatile small business owner meets the love of
his life after being threatened by a gang of scammers.
Barry Egan, played by Adam Sandler.
Lena Leonard, played by Emily Watson.
Dean Trumbell, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Lance, played by Luis Guzmán.
Elizabeth Egan, played by Mary Lynn Rajskub.
Walter the Dentist, played by Robert Smigel.
Punch-Drunk Love is a 2002 American absurdist romantic comedy drama film,
produced, written and directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
Adam Sandler stars as an entrepreneur with social anxiety who falls in
love with his sister's co-worker, played by Emily Watson.
The supporting cast includes Philip Seymour Hoffman and Luis Guzmán.
After working on his third film Magnolia, Anderson planned to make his next film around 90
minutes, with Sandler in mind as the lead due to Anderson's love for him and his films.
It features the video art of Jeremy Blake in the form of visual interludes.
Punch-Drunk Love was produced by Columbia Pictures, Revolution Studios, New Line Cinema
and Ghoulardi Film Company, and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It premiered at the 2002 Cannes Film Festival on May 19, 2002 before being
released theatrically in the United States on November 1, 2002.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with
Sandler's performance receiving widespread acclaim.
However, the film was a box-office disappointment, grossing $24.7
million against its $25 million production budget.
A favorite of several prominent filmmakers, it has been included in
lists of the greatest movies of the 21st century.
It was also a launchpad for Sandler to pursue dramatic or
unconventional film roles outside of his usual mainstream comedies.
The film explores themes of depression, sibling
relationship, businessman, shyness, hawaii.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.